{
    "id": "7acd6a7bf2a8496cb4dd165d2560dc48",
    "title": "Little, Few, Likely, Long | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "60c6e872b63640fe8d3b20ec9067af1c",
            "title": "Little, Few, Likely",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Are you ………………………….. to be staying in this evening?",
                    "description": "Be likely can be followed by a to-infinitive. Probable is not used in this way.",
                    "answers": [
                        "likely",
                        "probable",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is likely …………………………….",
                    "description": "When ‘it’ is the subject, be likely is usually followed by a that-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for the meeting to be postponed",
                        "that the meeting will be postponed",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. politicians are really honest.",
                    "description": "We use few with plural nouns and little with uncountable nouns.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Few",
                        "Little",
                        "Less"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Could I try ……………………… soup?",
                    "description": "Little has a rather negative meaning. A little is closer to some.",
                    "answers": [
                        "little",
                        "a little",
                        "few"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Only …………………………. my students like mathematics.",
                    "description": "We use few of before a noun with a determiner.",
                    "answers": [
                        "a few",
                        "a few of",
                        "a little of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………….. people can claim that they always tell the truth.",
                    "description": "Before a noun without a determiner, we use few.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Few",
                        "Few of",
                        "Little",
                        "Little of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………. us can claim that we always tell the truth.",
                    "description": "Before a pronoun we use few of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Few",
                        "Few of",
                        "Little of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Could I have a …………………………. the soup?",
                    "description": "Before a noun with a determiner, we use little of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "little more",
                        "few more of",
                        "little more of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You don’t need to go shopping. We have got …………………. bacon.",
                    "description": "A little is similar to some. Little has a negative meaning. It means almost nothing.",
                    "answers": [
                        "little",
                        "a little",
                        "a few"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The movie was ………………………… interesting",
                    "description": "We cannot use little to modify other adjectives or adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "not very",
                        "little"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She seldom stays ………………………",
                    "description": "In questions and negatives we usually use long.",
                    "answers": [
                        "long",
                        "for a long time",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We have been waiting ………………………..",
                    "description": "In affirmative clauses, we usually prefer for a long time. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "long",
                        "for a long time",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}